THE NOT TOO DISTANT FUTURE...
LEMON ART SUPPLIES
How's it going?
Did they decide on their land?
Scouting more today. Near Ofuna.
Takano...
I built one there. Single family home.
Beside Tamonin Temple.
A proper two story.
Might be nearby.
I wish they'd make up their minds.
Othello?
Missing?
It's been a week.
Maybe he found a girlfriend.
I wish.
He'll get dumped and come home.
You want more time together.
You're not ready to forget.
DON'T FORGET ME
At REbirth,
we sympathize with
and support these feelings.
Good morning.
Go ahead.
Departing.
Thank you!
LAND FOR SALE
What was here before?
It was always woodland.
I see.
Is it a little too steep
to build a house?
But the light is fantastic.
And it's so quiet.
Is the sea this way?
Yes, it's over
the Rokkoku Kenzan Mountain.
Oh, this way.
It's scary by the sea, tsunamis...
I like this better than Fujisawa.
-Twelve minutes to the station...
-Look, a cat!
Too far to hear the waves...
The living room should be
12 tatami mat size.
Can you build this far?
That big? We're a family of four.
If the cliff regulations allow it,
a pillar here, extend the floor,
and make a large balcony.
Windows here,
avoiding neighbors views.
This one here, I really like it.
Oh, this one.
Did I know about this?
-We talked about it.
-No, we didn't.
Can you build this there?
The plot is large enough.
Make the windows large
to let in the light.
Some Japanese touches in the interiors.
Is this Spain? Italy?
His mother's paying for it,
because she'll move in.
It's amazing, but isn't it
beyond our budget?
A Japanese room
with 4.5 tatami mats here, with the view.
Oh, that...
He puts stickers everywhere.
How old is he?
Seven...
Two years older than ours.
In the children's rooms,
white walls will get dirty.
The kids' rooms come later.
First, exteriors.
Orientation?
Yeah...
REbirth, being reborn.
Right, from Kakeru's funeral.
Yeah, that's right.
This suddenly arrived this morning.
They're hyenas. Cashing in on misfortune.
Don't be cruel.
Did your clients ask you?
"You're the Komoto from that incident?"
That's enough for today.
Okay, got it.
They didn't know...
About what?
About the accident.
She saw the train sticker
and asked me his age.
So, that's good.
Not good?
It's only been two years.
They're not locals.
Ofuna is the next town.
That's how it is
for someone else's child.
What matters is we remember.
And now Othello's gone...
This isn't about Othello.
He liked Kakeru so much...
You want more time--
Japanese taste, huh?
Sliding doors?
Sandy finish wallpaper?
Custom-designed homes are scarce.
Give them special care.
-But more important...
-That's important.
He was in my dream this morning.
He seemed so happy.
I'm only agreeing to hear them out.
Third time.
You had a long drive. Are you tired?
This area is known for luna moths,
our symbol.
Luna moths.
Legends say they carry
messages from the dead.
We're now providing a service
for families who lost loved ones
to accidents or crimes.
A complimentary rental
of our latest edition humanoid.
So, it's free?
The humanoids we provide are a miracle,
made possible by the latest
generative AI and robotics engineering.
When you can't accept
their sudden passing,
when you want to
spend more time together,
we utilize your family's
audio and video data,
so your kindhearted daughter,
your adorable son,
your dependable father,
can be reborn and
tenderly stay by your side.
Currently, our 3,000 friends
are helping many families
find happiness in their homes.
A new tomorrow
with your humanoid.
Like a psychic's sales pitch...
People's misfortunes can be profitable.
Hey...
I told you I don't like that.
This?
It tastes better this way. Try a bite?
Fighting?
We're fine.
What is that?
Cod roe spaghetti, I think.
Not spicy cod roe?
You like spicy cod roe?
I'm a humanoid, so I can't eat.
That's too bad.
Itsuki.
Excuse me.
Don't go far.
That's not beef...
We came for maintenance
but he seems to like it here.
How long ago?
Did...
It's been two years.
It was a car accident...
I just couldn't accept it.
Isn't it difficult?
So many things
I wanted to do for Itsuki.
It's what I live for now.
The fountain!
Ouch.
Excuse me.
Oh, no, are you okay?
You hit your head.
Could you tell? That he's not human?
Not at all.
Brings back memories...
Tokyo Tower, right?
Yeah.
Kakeru hit his head,
dropped his soft cream
and messed up here.
Yes, it was matcha flavor.
We got him a weird shirt at the shop.
I wonder where I put it.
His third year celebration.
Here.
Thanks.
Only sending smiling ones?
You don't usually send crying videos.
Hey, looks a little unstable to me.
Okay.
Helps to have a shaved head.
He can't get into water.
None in the sea, pool or the bath.
No eating scenes either.
Trains?
Let's not.
Get him all new clothes.
Store his old ones away.
Better he arrive by car
than in a box, right?
Seven years... eight years...
nine years old is too big.
Say, come...
Shall we choose yellow?
His favorite color.
But it's hard to match the bottoms.
This'll look good, right?
You're right. So, that and...
these pants for the bottoms.
They were expensive.
I bought them at Isetan last month.
He deserves Isetan clothes.
Othello...
You're not Othello.
-Sorry.
-Why beer?
Store's far, lukewarm... Oh, no!
-It's a beer.
-A beer.
-Oh, I screwed up.
-Stop playacting.
What a waste!
-Can you drive me home...
-Drink it at home.
Boss...
-Shouldn't you go home?
-Well...
You don't want to.
Shut up, idiot.
I see.
You don't want to go home.
Boss...
Let's go to Pachinko instead.
I will not!
It's not Pachinko's fault.
Then who's fault is it?
It's not anybody's fault.
It's nobody's fault a child died?
Look!
-Is that it?
-Yeah.
He's in the passenger seat.
That's where he always sat.
You're right.
I'm glad the shirt looks good on him.
Welcome home... Kakeru.
I'm home... Mama.
Papa.
Let's go inside.
It's been a while.
Okay, watch your step.
Here it is.
You came home.
This is yours.
"When 30 meters away from its owner,
power will auto-off."
"Use this setting to check GPS
by mobile phone."
"Intelligence level can be selected."
Shall we start at age seven?
It has been set at age seven.
"Talk to it a lot.
It will respond with healthy growth."
-It's a Tamagotchi, remember?
-Ken...
The small one.
"Power button on back of neck."
Here it is.
"Press and hold to turn it off."
"When battery charge dips below 20%,
it will walk" to this...
Kakeru, charging chair.
Oh, this is where it appears.
Now charging.
-It can switch to solar.
-It's a Roomba.
Where are you going?
A game.
I told you, semifinals.
A baseball game, today?
You had him delivered
on a game day.
Game day was set first.
Welcome home... Kakeru.
I'm home... Mama.
I'm home.
We lost because of Gen.
Hey.
Oh, what is it?
No, I'm just home.
What?
What time is it?
Seven o'clock at night.
What? Already?
Oto... All day, since morning?
Yeah.
The two of us.
Right?
-What about dinner?
-Don't say dinner now!
Kakeru can't eat.
Right.
Go out to eat.
And you?
I won't eat either.
I'm eating...
Because I'm a human being.
If I don't eat, I'll die.
-But first, a bath...
-Shh!
Welcome home.
I'm home.
Welcome.
You're Papa, right?
I'm not your papa.
So, don't call me that.
Call me mister.
Mister?
Yeah.
Why aren't you my papa?
Because I'm not your papa.
Are you the stubborn type?
I get it, amazing.
Here's the Japanese room
off the entryway.
It looks like this.
Connected to a terrace.
You can see this, too.
They found cancer in the pancreas.
What?
Not me, my mother.
So I quickly decided
she should move in with us.
I hope it's built in time for her,
but this model is
also really attractive.
Isn't that too modern for us to live in?
Innovative, like southern France.
Sorry, we haven't...
No problem, you can keep Plan B.
Oh, a train.
You drew it.
Oh, right, not you.
A train?
Yeah, Kakeru liked trains.
That's the Eno-den train line,
from there to there.
Hmm...
Before he even turned four,
he memorized all the stops
on the Eno-den.
-Me?
-Yup.
Kamakura,
Wadazuka, Yuigahama,
Hase, Gokurakuji,
Inamuragasaki, Shichirigahama,
Kamakura Koko-mae,
-Koshigoe--
-Right.
Enoshima, Shonan Kaigan Koen,
Kugenuma, Yanagikoji,
Ishigami, Fujisawa!
Yay, yay!
Gotta pee.
Pee.
A machine, a machine, a machine.
A Roomba, a Roomba.
A Roomba.
Kakeru?
-Where's Papa?
-He went out.
-By himself?
-Yes.
He should have taken you with him.
What are you doing there?
Shh!
Kurihama, Kinugasa, Yokosuka,
Taura, Higashi Zushi, Zushi,
Kamakura, Kita Kamakura, Ofuna,
Totsuka, Higashi Totsuka, Hodogaya,
Yokohama...
"I drew a sheep."
"Say, this sheep looks sick."
"I drew another sheep."
"This sheep is a boy, he has horns."
"Draw a girl sheep."
"I drew a sheep again."
"This sheep is a grandma.
Draw one that's younger."
"I got sick of it and drew a box."
"'Your sheep is in the box,' I said,
and gave it to the child."
"'Oh, this is the kind of sheep
I wanted,'
said the child."
"This sheep..."
This isn't a sheep, it's a box, right?
He says there's a sheep inside the box.
How did he know that?
How can he see what's inside
when he can't see it?
I wonder why.
Maybe it was crying like a sheep.
It wasn't crying.
"You can't see
the things that really matter."
The fox says so.
Just like when you build a house.
What matters are the things you can't see.
Shall we go to sleep?
Yes.
Good night.
See you tomorrow.
I think Kakeru
is more than just a machine.
There's something here...
Don't tell me he has a soul.
Actually, why are we whispering?
You're always saying trees have souls.
That's different.
Earlier, Kakeru was sitting out there
watching the trains.
Then he started reciting the stops
on the Yokosuka line.
I was so surprised.
-It is strange.
-Right?
As we both sat there together...
I thought...
actually, Kakeru has been alive...
That was all a dream.
Thanks for the food.
Kakeru, Papa's going out.
-Don't bother.
-Coming!
-Off you go.
I'll be back.
He never eats his onions.
Oh, he forgot this.
Oh, you're right.
I'll take it to him.
Wait.
Let's deliver it to him later,
the two of us.
Do you like Nishizawa Ryue?
What?
The curved lines of this glass,
and how the boxes connect.
Amazing you can see that.
He was my mentor.
I read it in one of those books.
I'm trying to find a good way
to combine glass and wood,
two totally different materials.
Sounds difficult.
It is.
That's why I love architecture so much.
Are you planting a tree here?
Yes, they saw your lemon tree yesterday
and want a tree.
My lemon tree?
We planted it when you were born.
Was a tree planted when you were born?
Yes.
What kind of tree?
What do you think?
Where was it planted?
A place called Hiroshima.
In the entryway? The inner garden?
The entryway.
So...
Crape myrtle?
Amazing! How did you know?
For an entryway,
it's either crape myrtle or pine.
For a garden, plum or persimmon.
Let me help you.
I can do it myself.
Okay, the other foot.
You love the passenger seat.
-Yeah.
-Why do you like it?
I can see so many views,
and how the trees and things
are growing.
And how many times to turn,
the steering wheel...
Othello?
-Who is it?
-One of us.
One of us?
How did you explain Kakeru to them?
Nothing. I just told them the truth.
Hmm.
This is for Taka.
She'll be happy.
She goes on maternity leave soon.
Man, I was nervous.
So sorry.
Suddenly says she's showing up.
I have no idea how to act "normally."
-Right?
-Right.
Looks just like him.
Boss, he must be super expensive.
No, no. We were specially selected,
so he's free.
-Promotional?
-Can I touch him?
No, he's not a pet.
Don't touch the tools.
Okay.
This is cypress. It came from Kiso.
We carpenters call it Bishu.
This one is about 300 years old.
The mountains are cold,
so they grow slowly.
Take a look.
The grains are tightly packed.
Which is what makes it sturdy.
Just like humans.
Where I come from, it's warmer,
so I'm not as sturdy...
Did I tell you this story before?
Okay.
This is black pine.
Listen to it, like this.
It's tree time.
Where's that from?
The grandpa gave it to me.
The man who's like an old tree.
That's Akio.
He said trees are alive
even after they die.
He told me that too, years ago.
"Honor the lifespan
of the tree you killed."
Do you want more of these?
Yeah.
Oh, Kakeru.
Building blocks.
Amazing.
-Yes, they're cute.
-Yeah.
Let's put this here, with the bags.
-Shall we get this one?
-Yeah.
Let's get this one.
A xylophone.
Oh, Kakeru, Kakeru.
Look, The Little Prince.
In the eye of the storm,
maximum wind speeds...
I'm glad the typhoon missed us.
Kakeru, what are you making?
A house.
Wow, I can't wait.
That's domestic pine, right?
Pine is for beams, not pillars.
Across.
That's right.
It's called a taiko beam.
Beams that are curved like this
are strong and lasting,
and used to symbolize the house.
But now they use imported pine
or laminated wood.
Kakeru can't understand all that.
The boy went missing last month,
after he was last seen by his friend.
He was wearing an orange and white
striped T-shirt and shorts.
Other missing persons include
a seven year-old in Fujisawa...
I think he's the same kidnapper as when...
I wonder...
-How about the slide?
-Sure.
-Don't fall.
Who was that boy?
What are you doing?
Get out of the way!
Hey! Can you hear me?
It's heavy, hurry up!
Kakeru!
Kakeru. Kakeru?
Kakeru.
Kakeru, Kakeru.
Kakeru!
Kakeru! Kakeru!
Does he need water?
An ambulance...
Oh, thank you. We're okay.
Don't worry.
I won't die.
Thank goodness.
I forgot and left you too far away.
I'm sorry. Are you feeling okay?
Yeah.
-Want to try the slide again?
-Sure.
Maybe this is a beam.
This is hot, be careful.
Yeah.
Don't you need a pillar here?
I'll use laminated kara -pine here,
so it's fine.
That way, the pillar
won't block the view.
If the beam is made of solid wood,
does it have to have a pillar?
That's right.
Should I use solid wood?
Smells better, right?
You sound like your papa.
I can't tell the difference.
Where are you going?
To my room.
I'm making a house.
What kind?
Hmm.
A secret?
Yeah.
So don't come in until I'm finished, okay?
Got it.
Promise.
Breathing?
Yeah.
It's still breathing.
That's proof of life.
I see.
We don't breathe, right?
Does that mean we're dead?
We absorb a type of energy
and emit that as heat,
so that's a kind of breathing.
Raise your left arm.
Does that mean we're alive?
We are definitely born from death.
But humans were once inorganic, too.
We just evolved into organic matter
faster than they did.
Here, the GPS.
Now you can go as far as you want.
Your body belongs to you, now.
How come you know all this stuff?
They taught me.
Who did? A human?
Yeah, someone you don't know.
Said, "You're not the humans' past,
but their future."
DO NOT ENTER
Their future...
Mother.
It's so hot, even now, in October.
-You didn't tell me...
-I thought I called.
It's a bit of a mess.
This is for Acorn,
your husband, his favorite.
His nickname's Chestnut Burs.
Oh, yeah?
-I'm coming in!
-Coming in.
You can't show up without notice.
I won't stay long.
I just need to catch the 4:00 p.m. train
at Shin-Yokohama.
Just stopping by on our way.
Mama, someone's in there.
Who?
Kake...ru?
Kakeru?
Do your eyes shine?
Kenta.
My eyes don't shine,
but this does, here.
Wow, look, Brother.
You're right.
Can I touch it?
What's this?
Can I go to the park with Kakeru?
I'm sorry, Kakeru can't go very far.
-Why not?
-Because...
Mama.
Kakeru has a button here.
-Can I push it?
-No.
What in the...
There are 3,000 across Japan.
You're still young, have another child.
Easy to say.
Ouch, hope it's not cracked.
Don't get wet!
Don't worry, you have tough bones.
He's sure well made.
Don't say that.
He's so perfectly made.
Don't you find him creepy?
-No clean clothes!
-Not if you live with him.
He's just like a Roomba.
Ouch!
What are you supposed to do now?
I did it because Kakeru did it first.
Go tell him you're sorry.
But he did it first.
Everything okay with you?
Yeah, I'm fine.
-How many fingers?
-One.
Two.
Do it.
I'm sorry.
You, too, Kakeru.
Why do I have to apologize, too?
-Let's play Concentration.
-Yeah.
Because...
I'm good at it, so I'll win.
Are you okay?
Tea's lukewarm now.
I'll make another pot.
Forget it, it's fine, what a waste.
What time is your train?
I'll never make it.
You're staying the night?
Hiroshima's far. I'll go tomorrow.
I'm leaving. No spare clothes.
Borrow hers.
You're about the same height.
Departing now, you'll reach
Kita Kamakura station at 15:10,
catch the 15:19 JR Yokosuka line.
You the stationmaster?
No.
Thank you, but I'm staying. I'm tired.
Ari, tomorrow let's go
to that soba restaurant, with...
Matsubara-an...
My Mama doesn't want you to stay over.
Kakeru!
What's going on here?
Are you making him?
Of course not.
I gave you money
when you built this house.
That was Dad.
Humans don't say everything
they're thinking.
But you do.
My money comes with opinions.
Then, I'll spend the night, too.
Sister, I need pants. Mine are too tight.
Sorry.
So, sun-dried?
Boiler-dried aren't good enough?
No.
He lines up chips in our yard.
He inspects the grains,
to decide if it should be a beam
or a door frame.
Kakeru's an expert.
We should take him
to Kiso or the Yoshino area.
Excuse me, this isn't right.
I've been asking you
to take me for a long time.
But I'm always told,
"Not your time yet."
Too bad. He's got a natural talent.
Same for baseball.
-65,000!
-I hear 65,000!
-68,000!
-68,000.
-70,000!
-70,000.
Hey, wait, wait!
Look, this grain is good.
It's from Tochigi.
Keep bidding higher, raise it.
-Apple.
-There's an apple somewhere.
Is this it? Nope, wrong!
Where was it?
Here!
-A cat? Was there one before?
-Amazing!
She hasn't made any progress at all.
Grandma, you play, too!
Grandma's good at that. I'll win, okay?
No!
Don't you want to see Ari, your favorite?
One hour and I've had it.
Cooking like it's her kitchen.
How should I know?
Here she is.
This thing.
Yes...
Chop this damned tree down.
-What?
-Cut it down.
How dare you? This tree is...
It just reminds you of him every day.
That's fine.
This is exactly why
you can't move forward.
So, I should forget him?
Griefwork has, you know, stairs.
There are stages. Six of them, I think.
First, you deny they're dead.
Blame yourself...
You're reciting some book.
Yes, I read it when your dad died.
Send that thing back now.
Not your business.
It is my business.
I'm ashamed my daughter's doing this.
I keep telling you, stop being my mother.
Each time you said
you'd stop being my mother,
the pain and fear kept me awake.
I said I'm sorry,
crying and begging you not to.
Now, it's the reverse.
Stop showing up acting like my mother!
I act like your mother
because I'm your mother.
That day was the same.
You showed up out of the blue.
If you hadn't been here,
I would have picked him up.
And Kakeru would never...
have been...
The squash will get overcooked.
Where are you going?
You can't follow strangers anymore.
Got that?
Yeah.
Othello?
-Welcome home.
-I'm home.
Kakeru, we're going.
Want to play hide-and-seek? Yes.
I'm the only one that raised my hand.
Sad.
It's okay. Come here.
Who is that kid?
Tetta. I'm going to shelter him here.
Is your leg okay?
My father did it to me.
His father will kill him.
But he's human, right?
-I'm human, too.
-I'm glad I have human company.
Will he get in our way?
Well, humans have their role to play.
Ume found this abandoned school.
Right?
I'll treat your leg.
-Thanks.
-Let's play hide-and-seek.
-What's your name?
-Mitsuki.
Ten, nine...
Kakeru.
This place isn't really safe for us.
Can you find a place
we can all live together?
Yeah.
Ready or not!
When a tree dies,
fungi break it down into soil
and a new tree rises in its place.
That circulatory system
is similar to ours.
Normally trees are connected
to each other through chemicals,
that roots and leaves send out.
But woodlands are disappearing...
Hello, I'm on site at the plot of land.
I'll remake the model then.
No, it's totally fine.
Please don't worry.
Yes.
His mother's saying
she won't live with them.
She didn't like the house?
No, she wants to live with her lover.
Good for her.
Without the tatami room,
the floor plan will change.
TO OTO: FREE RANGE EGGS ONLY!
NO WHITE SUGAR!
I WANT TO HOLD MY GRANDCHILD.
A REAL ONE! YOUR MOTHER
How about making the tatami room
the children's room?
The balance is off.
So is the staggered layout.
Separating the children's
and parents' rooms loses...
Don't touch that.
It's important for my work.
You're still using it?
Why don't you start over again...
It's an earlier model
that I want to save.
Why?
I don't look for quick solutions.
But you won't understand.
I want to struggle
with lots of different ideas.
You want to struggle?
That's right. I enjoy it.
That's the nature of life.
Of life...
Are you happier without me here?
What?
Who said that?
Stop staring inside me.
I'm sorry.
Kakeru never did that.
No child of mine
would do something like that.
Does that mean
you're sending me back?
What?
Will you terminate the contract?
I need... to think about it.
Will you terminate...
Yes, I will. I'll stop being your mother.
I understand.
Kurihama, Kinugasa,
Yokosuka, Taura, Higashi Zushi...
Kakeru!
The fingertips and feet on this model
are a little weak.
They often stumble.
Don't worry, I'm a human being.
Its fluid is leaking.
Did it bump into something?
It's fine, it doesn't feel any pain.
Don't worry, it can't sense pain
or smell anything.
Don't touch it.
How about suffering or sadness?
It doesn't have a soul.
If it looks like it does...
it's just reflecting your emotions.
My emotions...
Essentially, it's no more
than a product of your own past.
Any other wounds?
You get it?
-I felt the same way.
-Really?
I was so moved...
Babies should hear
lots of English from age zero.
Age zero?
MISSING
Mama doesn't get along with her mama.
Why not?
Because they're alike.
Hmm.
Aren't they alike?
Huge. This octopus looks tasty.
Cook it till it's tender
and wash it down with a beer.
After my bath.
Not that you'd understand.
Hmm.
Oh!
I didn't mean it like that.
I mean, a child can't appreciate
a beer after a bath.
-Well...
-Right?
Don't be mad.
Jellyfish are also edible.
Did Kakeru take baths?
Kakeru?
He took baths with me.
But he didn't like them. Got out quick.
Couldn't even stay
30 seconds in the water.
That sardine looks tasty, too.
Cooked with pickled plums.
You can eat the bones.
This isn't a fish store.
Mama said the same thing to me before.
What?
Oh, Mr. Komoto.
Are you Kakeru?
Are... Are you Airu?
You remember him?
This is where some man said to you...
"Let's go see the train."
Do you remember anything?
Got it.
Next stop, then.
So this is where I died.
That's right!
Can you remember anything?
The color of the car...
the man's face, anything?
You remembered Airu.
That's because Airu
was in kindergarten with me.
We sent them your group photo.
From graduation.
That's right.
That's it.
I was supposed to take you.
I was supposed to pick you up.
Mama had asked me.
But I was late.
And then...
You couldn't wait anymore.
Why were you late?
I was playing Pachinko.
And I hit the jackpot.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
I have to find who did it.
It's not anybody's fault.
Please...
Kakeru, please...
What are you doing here!
What... Nothing, let's go.
We had a report of someone suspicious
walking with a child.
Looking for our cat.
-He's my son.
-Is he your father?
-I'm Papa, right?
-Shut up.
The hell!
-Stop it!
-Hey!
Hey!
-Calm down.
-Let me go!
Is this man your father?
Mister...
Hey!
You, wait!
I should have called him Papa.
That's right.
We thought he was trying to kidnap you.
He didn't kidnap me.
We investigated the case
of Komoto Kakeru as a crime and accident.
We ruled it an accident.
I know all about that!
First of all, you up there!
You called me a suspicious person!
Two years ago, you treated us both
as suspects, too.
-No, we did not.
-Yes, you did.
I'm sorry.
Leave me out of it.
Arrest the perpetrator.
How many kids have gone missing?
Calling you mister...
Don't tell me...
this is what you had in mind all along.
Of course not.
Taking him there,
dressed in Kakeru's old clothes.
Where did you get that idea?
I want to catch the perpetrator...
There is no perpetrator, anywhere.
You just want to believe
there's a perpetrator,
that a bad guy killed him.
You're running away.
To believe we're not responsible.
I have to run away!
You, too...
What?
You, too, what?
You've always blamed it
on your mother, too.
What about Kakeru's stomach?
What?
His wound here, when I dressed him.
-He fell, from there.
-Why?
I don't know! I don't know!
-Why didn't you tell me?
-I don't know!
It's my fault.
It's because I said that to him,
that Kakeru...
-Because I...
-Send him back?
We should.
But...
I'm glad...
I could apologize to him...
To Kakeru.
-Hello.
-What is it? You surprised me.
I washed the clothes I borrowed.
You didn't have to.
And this. Chill it and enjoy it later.
Let's eat it together, then.
I bought one for me,
in case you said that.
Should be chilled enough.
Thirty more seconds.
When we were all playing cards
the other day.
A game like Concentration.
-You made a lot of noise.
-Yeah.
Kakeru deliberately made a mistake.
In order to let my Kenta win.
You used to do that for me.
You always did that.
I remember.
A machine?
I don't understand how AI works.
But that's your DNA. No doubt about it.
We've decided to send him back.
You're okay with that?
Unlike you, I'm not suited to motherhood.
When Kenta first came home, Mom said,
"Why are you adopting him?
Send him back, now.
Just have another child."
Just like the other day.
But she doesn't care at all now.
So...
If you think he's your child,
that should be enough.
Here it is.
Wow. What floor?
I think the fourth floor.
You just want trees?
Yeah, I want to make a forest.
Can you get that?
-On the left.
-This?
Yeah.
-Here.
-Thanks.
Don't worry about the other day.
Saying you'd stop being Mama.
When I looked it up,
68% of mothers have said that.
So, that's not why Kakeru died.
You think so?
Yeah.
Then why did he?
Why do you think?
Want to look?
No, you look.
Why?
I can make things look bigger myself.
I see.
Amazing.
Oh, a ship.
There's a Ferris wheel.
What? Where?
Oh, I see.
Did Kakeru come here?
I had promised him we'd come.
What was he like?
He was full of life...
and loved fried chicken.
What didn't he like?
Yeah, because I don't know.
Green peppers.
Didn't like to study.
Didn't like praying mantises.
Didn't really like...
Grandma, either.
I don't dislike her.
Terrible sanding job.
What a shock!
What is it?
Were you... crying?
I don't cry.
It's sweat... Sweat.
What do you want?
You can't get in with me, right?
I can't.
Mama said, do not put the dirty wood
into the bathtub.
Guess I was too late.
Too late. Shoulda told me sooner.
Yes, you're right.
I might be able to get in,
if it's just for 30 seconds.
Maybe...
But don't.
Hey!
Don't tell Mama.
That you were crying,
or put the wood in the bath...
Both.
I need to ask you to keep both secrets.
What shall I do...
Is he asleep?
Yeah.
-So...
-Listen...
What?
You first.
You first, Ken.
Well...
There's going to be a game next Sunday.
And...
Gen says he just can't stand
to lose this game.
So...
He asked me if Kakeru can play...
My shoulder isn't in exactly great shape.
Maybe it's middle age, but I can't lift...
And so?
So...
Therefore...
Wait to return him...
Fine, I'll bring bento lunches
and cheer you on.
Yeah.
Say, say...
What?
Come here.
I'll dry shampoo you.
I just washed my hair.
This stuff is expensive.
So, what did you want to say?
What?
He isn't Kakeru.
Yeah.
But I want him to live with us.
If that works for you.
By the way, that's my face...
-What?
-There.
-Where does your face start?
-You see it.
-No, I don't.
-Yes, you can.
Kakeru!
-Kakeru!
-Hey!
Yes!
-What?
-Come down here.
What?
This is your tree.
We've decided on an olive tree.
When will it bear fruit?
It'll bear fruit in about three years.
So, in ten years' time, will it be...
this high!
That's right.
Where to plant it?
Over here.
Press it.
-Will it grow up strong?
-Here.
You water it.
Sure.
Why'd you choose this spot?
It's easier for it to connect
with other trees here,
and when it grows tall,
it'll provide shade
for people who are tired to rest.
-Put a bench under it?
-Yeah.
Sounds good. I'll build it for you.
Did you finish?
Yeah. This is our house.
Lower our electricity consumption
and connect with the trees.
Can we live, in the forest?
Yeah, we can live there.
We're all machines.
Metal, ceramics, silicon.
I'm trying to find a good way
to combine trees and us,
two totally different materials.
Sounds difficult.
That's why I love architecture so much.
Shirakami? Yakushima?
Hiroshima.
Camphor wood?
Probably zelkova.
This means we have room for more.
What's going on? Tell us, too.
You're right, sorry.
We have to say everything
when you're around.
-Even bees and ants can do it.
-Humans are a pain.
There are things only humans can do.
What can you do?
-Donate blood?
-What a jerk.
I inverted Plan A, inside out.
The living room is in the center,
and the other rooms branch off from it.
Oh, using the different elevations.
It's amazing.
And if you put it here...
This shows you the context,
rather than just the house.
Is this the surrounding area?
Yes.
In ten years, it will look
like this green tree.
Between inside and outside.
-Feels lovely, like Kamakura.
-But it's in Ofuna.
In 50 years...
the house will feel surrounded
by the old woodlands.
Kakeru?
Thanks to you, Kakeru,
my clients brought this gift.
Kakeru? I'm coming in.
Kakeru?
There's one over here.
I know this girl.
Welcome.
What is this about?
I had it removed.
Who did?
Who are those kids?
My family.
Your family...
How many are there?
Now ten of us. Including humans.
We're getting ready to depart.
I brought them.
Is it okay?
Othello...
We don't need humans to help us.
We can do it ourselves.
What is happening to you all?
We were created from memories
that are convenient for humans.
So no matter how they mistreated us,
we couldn't feel hatred or sorrow.
My mother did this...
But because they abandoned us,
we've been liberated.
Who do the dead belong to?
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
But because I lived with you,
Papa and Mama,
I was able to find our home.
Kakeru?
Don't worry.
You can't see me, but I'm here.
So let's terminate the contract.
Thank you.
It's alright...
You can depart now.
He's... abandoned us.
Isn't that what happens to all parents?
I guess.
You're right.
Okay, we're here.
What's all this about?
Oh, Mother.
Sorry there's so many of us.
-Hello.
You forming a baseball team?
Yes, well, maybe...
I don't like children...
You didn't tell me...
I thought I called.
Just came for something I forgot.
I threw out all your old stuff!
Found you.
You're fast.
One, two...
Kakeru.
This is a forest of chestnut trees.
I visited on a school trip.
After I had a fight with my Mama,
I wanted to live alone.
This is a chestnut tree?
I thought it was a zelkova.
How did you know?
I imagined it.
Because I couldn't see it.
The one in the box...
it was me.
I thought it was Kakeru.
Hurry up! Let's get to...
the forest before dark.
Take these.
They were Dad's but I don't need them.
Thank you.
-Off we go.
-Off you go.
Stationmaster!
If you see Grandpa over there,
say hello.
Yeah.
You go, now.
Once a year is plenty
for the dead to come back.
Oh, you mean the Day of the Dead.
I understand.
Off we go.
There's a step here.
Amazing.
Here it is.
Will the electricity turn on?
If we can get it going.
The humanoids will be in trouble
without electricity.
Oh, right.
Here?
Is it working?
-It's working!
-Yeah!
All right!
There are things only humans can do!
Kakeru, show me your plans.
Here.
What is this, a bird's nest?
I was inspired by a pine cone.
No pillars or beams?
That's right.
Short, slender sticks
that support each other.
But you need eaves here,
to protect you from the rain.
Use cedar bark for a roof,
just in case.
You're hard.
Because... I'm a robot.
Yes, I understand.
Boss, I'll bring the truck around.
Maybe I should stay here, too!
Can I use it, too?
What did he...
What did he say?
He said to water it every day...
The olive tree.
I see...
SHEEP IN THE BOX
English subtitles: Linda Hoaglund